so if you were to imagine ain't looking
across at somebody and you were to look
into their eyes and you just started to
focus it on one of their eyeballs right
and you just began to tell them and
describe to them the intimate details of
what what you could notice going on in
their eyeball scribing the shape and the
color the white to the eyes the little
Pink's in the eyes the purples the
various shades of the retina right and
just imagine just like looking at the
person's eye and then you could just
imagine looking right at their eyeballs
still keeping your your gaze right there
and then I could say now switch from
looking at their eyeball to seeing them
it's interesting if I've that's a kind
of a mystery to me like what is that
like I'm looking at your eyeball when I
was looking at your eyeball and I was
describing your eyeball to you what I
saw was your eyeball in fact I was
describing to you what I could my scent
like I was basically looking to the
sensation of sight noticing all of the
colors and everything I could describe
right and then looking at the very same
spot shifting your gaze from seeing or
looking at your eyeball to seeing the
person you can imagine like I don't you
know you can just imagine that what
that's like and I that's an exercise
I've done a lot in circling to start to
get at this mystery right what is that
perception when you see them what
exactly are you perceiving
and what what were you what's the
difference between what you're
perceiving with when you're looking at
the eyeball to seeing them
I think that's a little bit starts to
speak towards with what the guy who made
the the last video was was attempting to
disclose or tease out
I'm I'm not so sure he did that great of
a job teasing it out but you know didn't
give the guy a break he's he's got a
deal with me haunting him with criticism
from the future after all
and
[Music]
you continue in this inquiry this some
question
about
essentially the question I would say at
least I know Heidegger would say this
like to awaken the question of being
right and what's at stake in that a
question becoming becoming awake to that
question and what's at stake there and
if we say that whatever it is that you
perceive when you perceive someone or
you shift from perceiving the eyeball to
see them may be analogous to something
like
when you shift your focal setting from
perceiving a being to receiving be aimed